spiegel.com 2012-06-14

# Spiegel | Privacy Policy - Spiegel

| Privacy Policy Statement  
---  
This is the Privacy Policy for Spiegel Catalog, Inc.  
Shopping online has changed our lives. At Spiegel your trust and satisfaction is of the utmost importance. Because we respect your privacy, we have instituted policies intended to ensure that your personal information is handled in a safe and responsible manner.  
This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through Spiegel’s website. We suggest that you review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may update it from time to time. This Policy was last revised on February 1, 2012.  
  
What information do we collect?

Every time you visit our website, our Web server automatically collects the following non-personally identifiable information: your Internet service provider’s address, the referring URL and, information on the pages you access on our site.

We also collect personally identifiable information that you provide, such as survey information and information you provide when you make a purchase, register your email address or sign-up for sweepstakes or contests. If you have visited our site before and provided us with your email address, we collect information on what pages you access or visit while on our site.

How do we use your information?

The information we collect is used:

  * to generally improve the content and layout of our Website
  * to improve the content and layout of our Website for individual visitors
  * to notify you about updates to our Website
  * to contact you for marketing purposes
  * for internal review

In some instances, we share some of your information with our parent company, subsidiaries and other affiliates (the “Spiegel Affiliates”) or other organizations for marketing purposes.

When you supply us with personal information to request a catalog or order a product, the information you provide will be added to our customer file (including your name, address, phone number and email address). You may receive periodic mailings or telephone contact from us with information on new products and services, discounts, special promotions or upcoming events that we offer. If you do not want to receive such mailings from Spiegel, then please [Click Here](http://www.spiegel.com/customer/privacy.aspx#contact) for information on where to reach us to remove yourself from our contact list.

We may send you email with information on new products and services, discounts, special promotions or upcoming events that are being offered. If you do not wish to receive such email from us in the future, please [Click Here](http://www.spiegel.com/customer/privacy.aspx#contact) for information on where to contact us to remove yourself from our email list or, click on the "opt-out" link on any email you receive from us. Please note that when you make a purchase and provide us with your email address, we may send you confirmation of your order via email even if you have chosen not to receive future email from us about our products and services. We may also contact you by mail or telephone if we have questions about your order.

We supply our customer file (including your name, address, phone number and email address) to certain Spiegel Affiliates. In addition to information provided to Spiegel Affiliates, we may also provide your name, address and phone number (but not your email address) to a select group of companies who are not Spiegel Affiliates and whose products you may find of interest. If you do not want us to share this information with these companies, we can put you on our "do-not-share" or "do not call" lists. Please [Click Here](http://www.spiegel.com/customer/privacy.aspx#contact) for information on where to contact us if you do not want us to share this information with Spiegel Affiliates or other third parties.

Note that Spiegel Affiliates and other third parties with whom we share your information have their own privacy statements, and those statements apply to your personal information when it is held by such Spiegel Affiliates or third parties. Please refer to the Spiegel Affiliate or third party privacy statements, as applicable, for further information on how those entities treat your personal information.

In some instances, we use third party companies to help us in providing our products and services to you, to assist us in managing customer information, to fulfill promotions and to communicate with you. Some of these third party service providers are given access to some or all of the information you provide to us, including your email address, and may use cookies on our behalf. These third party service providers are contractually restricted from using your information in any manner, other than in helping us to provide you with the products and services available from Spiegel. For more information about these companies, Click Here.

Spiegel may participate with certain reputable companies who offer you the ability to establish a membership that would enable you to participate in travel and entertainment programs. If you elect to activate a trial membership in the Spiegel Privilege Pass program we will provide your name, address and credit card information to Encore Marketing International, the Spiegel Privilege Pass service provider. Spiegel is not responsible for the privacy practices of the companies sponsoring these membership programs and we suggest you review the privacy policy of each company with whom you may be considering a membership.

We may share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when: (1) permitted or required by law; or, (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions; or, (3) investigating fraud which has already taken place. The information is not provided to these companies for marketing purposes.

We may buy or sell business assets or be acquired by or acquire other companies. In such transactions, personal information generally is one of the transferred business assets. In addition, in the event that we merge or consolidate with another entity or there is a change in control of Spiegel Catalog, Inc., or, if all, or substantially all, of the assets of Spiegel Catalog, Inc. are sold to a third party, we may transfer your personal information to the third party. This information may include your name, mailing address and email address among other information. Please know that if such a transfer takes place, the third party acquiring the information will be advised of your preferences about how we use your information. After the transfer takes place, use of your information is subject to the privacy statement of the third party that acquires it. You should check that company's privacy statement for information on how it will use your customer information.

Third party merchants "Presented by Spiegel"

If you make a purchase from a Merchant Site with a link originating from the Spiegel site or a Merchant catalog or website "presented by" Spiegel, the information you provide to that Merchant, such as your credit card number and contact information, is provided to the Merchant and not to Spiegel. Providing this information to the Merchant enables the transaction to take place. However, you should know that the Merchant may, if you do not advise them to the contrary, share your name and postal and email addresses with third parties, including Spiegel. You should also know that these Merchants have their own privacy and data collection practices and are not covered by the Spiegel privacy statement.

Merchants on the Spiegel site and those Merchants, who send catalogs or host websites "presented by" Spiegel, have separate privacy and data collection practices. We have no control over and therefore no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. For more information regarding Merchants appearing on Spiegel or other Merchants who send catalogs or host websites "presented by" Spiegel and their privacy policies, please see the Merchant's home page and click on their Information link or review the customer service section of any catalog you may receive from the Merchant.

Merchants that have links on the Spiegel site may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of these Merchants are not covered by the Spiegel privacy statement.

How do you know your information is secure?

When you see either a solid key icon or a locked padlock icon in your browser window, then your site is secured through Secure Sockets Layer. We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving your information on our site. If you do not see one of these icons, please contact your Internet service provider. When we transfer and receive certain types of sensitive information, such as financial information, we will redirect you to a secure server and notify you through a pop-up screen on our site. 

We have appropriate security measures in place in our facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site so you can feel comfortable and secure. 

Please note that email is not encrypted and is not considered a secure means of transmitting credit card numbers. 

Children's Privacy

Spiegel does not seek to solicit information from anyone under the age of thirteen (a "Child"). If a Child submits information to us through any part of our Website, and we know that the person submitting the information is a Child, we delete the information as soon as we discover it and do not use it for any purpose, nor do we disclose it to third parties. If your child has submitted personal information to us and you would like to request that such information be removed from our customer lists, you may contact us using the “contact us” information listed below, and we will honor your request. 

How can you update your information?

We will provide you access to the following information if you send us an email, call us or write to us: 

  * financial information (such as your credit card account information)
  * unique identifier information (your customer number or password)
  * transaction information (dates on which you made purchases, amounts and types of purchases)
  * contact information (your name, address, phone number)

We will evaluate each request and reply in an appropriate manner and form of communication that respects the security of the information you have requested. [Click Here](http://www.spiegel.com/customer/privacy.aspx#contact) for Contact Information. 

Changes to this privacy statement

From time to time, we may use the information you provide us for new, unanticipated uses not previously addressed in our Privacy Statement. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes on the privacy page of our Website to notify you of these changes, and the revised Privacy Statement will apply to all of your personal information that we have on file, provided, however, that we will continue to honor any past requests not to share your information with third parties. You should check our Website periodically for more information on how we use the data we collect. 

If there is a material change in the manner we use data we collect, we will update this Privacy Statement to reflect these changes. 

Conflict in terms

It is our goal to make our privacy practices easy to understand. We have created this easy-to-read Privacy Statement with that goal in mind. Some browsers utilize privacy enhancing technology to translate our Privacy Statement into a computer readable format. The technology then requires that the computer format be translated back into human readable format for you to read. This translation back into human readable format is often referred to as a "Policy Summary". It is possible that through these translations, the Policy Summary may unintentionally end up being inconsistent with the Privacy Statement upon which it is based. It might fail to address an issue or it might address an issue not raised in our Privacy Statement. For this reason, you should rely on our Privacy Statement as the most accurate and definitive description of our practices. 

Contact us

To contact us for any reason, including a request to be added to or taken off a list, or if you have any concerns or questions, please contact us: 

  * By mail: 

> Spiegel Customer Satisfaction  
>  One Spiegel Avenue  
>  Hampton, VA 23630-5367

  * By phone: 

> 1.800.474.5555

  * By email: 

Special Note: When you contact us, please provide us with your exact name and address as it appears on correspondence you have received from us. 

We are an active member of the Direct Marketing Association. [Click here](http://www.the-dma.org/index.php) for additional privacy information from the DMA. If you feel that this site is not following its stated information privacy policy, you may contact us at the above address(es) or phone number or at [clientservices@spiegel.com](mailto:clientservices@spiegel.com) or you may contact the DMA's Committee on Ethical Business Practices at [mgoldberger@the-dma.org](mailto:mgoldberger@the-dma.org).
